<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OpenClaw</title>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.13</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:30:23 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9846</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.13</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.13</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Discord: send voice messages with waveform previews from local audio files (including silent delivery). (#7253) Thanks @nyanjou.</li>
<li>Discord: add configurable presence status/activity/type/url (custom status defaults to activity text). (#10855) Thanks @h0tp-ftw.</li>
<li>Slack/Plugins: add thread-ownership outbound gating via <code>message_sending</code> hooks, including @-mention bypass tracking and Slack outbound hook wiring for cancel/modify behavior. (#15775) Thanks @DarlingtonDeveloper.</li>
<li>Agents: add synthetic catalog support for <code>hf:zai-org/GLM-5</code>. (#15867) Thanks @battman21.</li>
<li>Skills: remove duplicate <code>local-places</code> Google Places skill/proxy and keep <code>goplaces</code> as the single supported Google Places path.</li>
<li>Agents: add pre-prompt context diagnostics (<code>messages</code>, <code>systemPromptChars</code>, <code>promptChars</code>, provider/model, session file) before embedded runner prompt calls to improve overflow debugging. (#8930) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Outbound: add a write-ahead delivery queue with crash-recovery retries to prevent lost outbound messages after gateway restarts. (#15636) Thanks @nabbilkhan, @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Threading: auto-inject implicit reply threading so <code>replyToMode</code> works without requiring model-emitted <code>[[reply_to_current]]</code>, while preserving <code>replyToMode: "off"</code> behavior for implicit Slack replies and keeping block-streaming chunk coalescing stable under <code>replyToMode: "first"</code>. (#14976) Thanks @Diaspar4u.</li>
<li>Outbound/Threading: pass <code>replyTo</code> and <code>threadId</code> from <code>message send</code> tool actions through the core outbound send path to channel adapters, preserving thread/reply routing. (#14948) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Media: allow image-only inbound messages (no caption) to reach the agent instead of short-circuiting as empty text, and preserve thread context in queued/followup prompt bodies for media-only runs. (#11916) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Discord: route autoThread replies to existing threads instead of the root channel. (#8302) Thanks @gavinbmoore, @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Web UI: add <code>img</code> to DOMPurify allowed tags and <code>src</code>/<code>alt</code> to allowed attributes so markdown images render in webchat instead of being stripped. (#15437) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Telegram/Matrix: treat MP3 and M4A (including <code>audio/mp4</code>) as voice-compatible for <code>asVoice</code> routing, and keep WAV/AAC falling back to regular audio sends. (#15438) Thanks @azade-c.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: preserve outbound document filenames for web-session document sends instead of always sending <code>"file"</code>. (#15594) Thanks @TsekaLuk.</li>
<li>Telegram: cap bot menu registration to Telegram's 100-command limit with an overflow warning while keeping typed hidden commands available. (#15844) Thanks @battman21.</li>
<li>Telegram: scope skill commands to the resolved agent for default accounts so <code>setMyCommands</code> no longer triggers <code>BOT_COMMANDS_TOO_MUCH</code> when multiple agents are configured. (#15599)</li>
<li>Discord: avoid misrouting numeric guild allowlist entries to <code>/channels/<guildId></code> by prefixing guild-only inputs with <code>guild:</code> during resolution. (#12326) Thanks @headswim.</li>
<li>MS Teams: preserve parsed mention entities/text when appending OneDrive fallback file links, and accept broader real-world Teams mention ID formats (<code>29:...</code>, <code>8:orgid:...</code>) while still rejecting placeholder patterns. (#15436) Thanks @hyojin.</li>
<li>Media: classify <code>text/*</code> MIME types as documents in media-kind routing so text attachments are no longer treated as unknown. (#12237) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Inbound/Web UI: preserve literal <code>\n</code> sequences when normalizing inbound text so Windows paths like <code>C:\\Work\\nxxx\\README.md</code> are not corrupted. (#11547) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>TUI/Streaming: preserve richer streamed assistant text when final payload drops pre-tool-call text blocks, while keeping non-empty final payload authoritative for plain-text updates. (#15452) Thanks @TsekaLuk.</li>
<li>Providers/MiniMax: switch implicit MiniMax API-key provider from <code>openai-completions</code> to <code>anthropic-messages</code> with the correct Anthropic-compatible base URL, fixing <code>invalid role: developer (2013)</code> errors on MiniMax M2.5. (#15275) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Ollama/Agents: use resolved model/provider base URLs for native <code>/api/chat</code> streaming (including aliased providers), normalize <code>/v1</code> endpoints, and forward abort + <code>maxTokens</code> stream options for reliable cancellation and token caps. (#11853) Thanks @BrokenFinger98.</li>
<li>OpenAI Codex/Spark: implement end-to-end <code>gpt-5.3-codex-spark</code> support across fallback/thinking/model resolution and <code>models list</code> forward-compat visibility. (#14990, #15174) Thanks @L-U-C-K-Y, @loiie45e.</li>
<li>Agents/Codex: allow <code>gpt-5.3-codex-spark</code> in forward-compat fallback, live model filtering, and thinking presets, and fix model-picker recognition for spark. (#14990) Thanks @L-U-C-K-Y.</li>
<li>Models/Codex: resolve configured <code>openai-codex/gpt-5.3-codex-spark</code> through forward-compat fallback during <code>models list</code>, so it is not incorrectly tagged as missing when runtime resolution succeeds. (#15174) Thanks @loiie45e.</li>
<li>OpenAI Codex/Auth: bridge OpenClaw OAuth profiles into <code>pi</code> <code>auth.json</code> so model discovery and models-list registry resolution can use Codex OAuth credentials. (#15184) Thanks @loiie45e.</li>
<li>Auth/OpenAI Codex: share OAuth login handling across onboarding and <code>models auth login --provider openai-codex</code>, keep onboarding alive when OAuth fails, and surface a direct OAuth help note instead of terminating the wizard. (#15406, follow-up to #14552) Thanks @zhiluo20.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: add vLLM as an onboarding provider with model discovery, auth profile wiring, and non-interactive auth-choice validation. (#12577) Thanks @gejifeng.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: preserve Hugging Face auth intent in auth-choice remapping (<code>tokenProvider=huggingface</code> with <code>authChoice=apiKey</code>) and skip env-override prompts when an explicit token is provided. (#13472) Thanks @Josephrp.</li>
<li>Onboarding/CLI: restore terminal state without resuming paused <code>stdin</code>, so onboarding exits cleanly after choosing Web UI and the installer returns instead of appearing stuck.</li>
<li>Signal/Install: auto-install <code>signal-cli</code> via Homebrew on non-x64 Linux architectures, avoiding x86_64 native binary <code>Exec format error</code> failures on arm64/arm hosts. (#15443) Thanks @jogvan-k.</li>
<li>macOS Voice Wake: fix a crash in trigger trimming for CJK/Unicode transcripts by matching and slicing on original-string ranges instead of transformed-string indices. (#11052) Thanks @Flash-LHR.</li>
<li>Mattermost (plugin): retry websocket monitor connections with exponential backoff and abort-aware teardown so transient connect failures no longer permanently stop monitoring. (#14962) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Discord/Agents: apply channel/group <code>historyLimit</code> during embedded-runner history compaction to prevent long-running channel sessions from bypassing truncation and overflowing context windows. (#11224) Thanks @shadril238.</li>
<li>Outbound targets: fail closed for WhatsApp/Twitch/Google Chat fallback paths so invalid or missing targets are dropped instead of rerouted, and align resolver hints with strict target requirements. (#13578) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Gateway/Restart: clear stale command-queue and heartbeat wake runtime state after SIGUSR1 in-process restarts to prevent zombie gateway behavior where queued work stops draining. (#15195) Thanks @joeykrug.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: prevent scheduler silent-death races during runner reloads, preserve retry cooldown backoff under wake bursts, and prioritize user/action wake causes over interval/retry reasons when coalescing. (#15108) Thanks @joeykrug.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: allow explicit wake (<code>wake</code>) and hook wake (<code>hook:*</code>) reasons to run even when <code>HEARTBEAT.md</code> is effectively empty so queued system events are processed. (#14527) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Heartbeat: strip sentence-ending <code>HEARTBEAT_OK</code> tokens even when followed by up to 4 punctuation characters, while preserving surrounding sentence punctuation. (#15847) Thanks @Spacefish.</li>
<li>Agents/Heartbeat: stop auto-creating <code>HEARTBEAT.md</code> during workspace bootstrap so missing files continue to run heartbeat as documented. (#11766) Thanks @shadril238.</li>
<li>Sessions/Agents: pass <code>agentId</code> when resolving existing transcript paths in reply runs so non-default agents and heartbeat/chat handlers no longer fail with <code>Session file path must be within sessions directory</code>. (#15141) Thanks @Goldenmonstew.</li>
<li>Sessions/Agents: pass <code>agentId</code> through status and usage transcript-resolution paths (auto-reply, gateway usage APIs, and session cost/log loaders) so non-default agents can resolve absolute session files without path-validation failures. (#15103) Thanks @jalehman.</li>
<li>Sessions: archive previous transcript files on <code>/new</code> and <code>/reset</code> session resets (including gateway <code>sessions.reset</code>) so stale transcripts do not accumulate on disk. (#14869) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Status/Sessions: stop clamping derived <code>totalTokens</code> to context-window size, keep prompt-token snapshots wired through session accounting, and surface context usage as unknown when fresh snapshot data is missing to avoid false 100% reports. (#15114) Thanks @echoVic.</li>
<li>CLI/Completion: route plugin-load logs to stderr and write generated completion scripts directly to stdout to avoid <code>source <(openclaw completion ...)</code> corruption. (#15481) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>CLI: lazily load outbound provider dependencies and remove forced success-path exits so commands terminate naturally without killing intentional long-running foreground actions. (#12906) Thanks @DrCrinkle.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway + ACP: block high-risk tools (<code>sessions_spawn</code>, <code>sessions_send</code>, <code>gateway</code>, <code>whatsapp_login</code>) from HTTP <code>/tools/invoke</code> by default with <code>gateway.tools.{allow,deny}</code> overrides, and harden ACP permission selection to fail closed when tool identity/options are ambiguous while supporting <code>allow_always</code>/<code>reject_always</code>. (#15390) Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: breaking default-behavior change - canvas IP-based auth fallback now only accepts machine-scoped addresses (RFC1918, link-local, ULA IPv6, CGNAT); public-source IP matches now require bearer token auth. (#14661) Thanks @sumleo.</li>
<li>Security/Link understanding: block loopback/internal host patterns and private/mapped IPv6 addresses in extracted URL handling to close SSRF bypasses in link CLI flows. (#15604) Thanks @AI-Reviewer-QS.</li>
<li>Security/Browser: constrain <code>POST /trace/stop</code>, <code>POST /wait/download</code>, and <code>POST /download</code> output paths to OpenClaw temp roots and reject traversal/escape paths.</li>
<li>Security/Canvas: serve A2UI assets via the shared safe-open path (<code>openFileWithinRoot</code>) to close traversal/TOCTOU gaps, with traversal and symlink regression coverage. (#10525) Thanks @abdelsfane.</li>
<li>Security/WhatsApp: enforce <code>0o600</code> on <code>creds.json</code> and <code>creds.json.bak</code> on save/backup/restore paths to reduce credential file exposure. (#10529) Thanks @abdelsfane.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway: sanitize and truncate untrusted WebSocket header values in pre-handshake close logs to reduce log-poisoning risk. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Security/Audit: add misconfiguration checks for sandbox Docker config with sandbox mode off, ineffective <code>gateway.nodes.denyCommands</code> entries, global minimal tool-profile overrides by agent profiles, and permissive extension-plugin tool reachability.</li>
<li>Security/Audit: distinguish external webhooks (<code>hooks.enabled</code>) from internal hooks (<code>hooks.internal.enabled</code>) in attack-surface summaries to avoid false exposure signals when only internal hooks are enabled. (#13474) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Security/Onboarding: clarify multi-user DM isolation remediation with explicit <code>openclaw config set session.dmScope ...</code> commands in security audit, doctor security, and channel onboarding guidance. (#13129) Thanks @VintLin.</li>
<li>Agents/Nodes: harden node exec approval decision handling in the <code>nodes</code> tool run path by failing closed on unexpected approval decisions, and add regression coverage for approval-required retry/deny/timeout flows. (#4726) Thanks @rmorse.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes: harden <code>app.update</code> by requiring HTTPS and gateway-host URL matching plus SHA-256 verification, stream URL camera downloads to disk with size guards to avoid memory spikes, and stop signing release builds with debug keys. (#13541) Thanks @smartprogrammer93.</li>
<li>Routing: enforce strict binding-scope matching across peer/guild/team/roles so peer-scoped Discord/Slack bindings no longer match unrelated guild/team contexts or fallback tiers. (#15274) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Exec/Allowlist: allow multiline heredoc bodies (<code><<</code>, <code><<-</code>) while keeping multiline non-heredoc shell commands blocked, so exec approval parsing permits heredoc input safely without allowing general newline command chaining. (#13811) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Config: preserve <code>${VAR}</code> env references when writing config files so <code>openclaw config set/apply/patch</code> does not persist secrets to disk. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Config: remove a cross-request env-snapshot race in config writes by carrying read-time env context into write calls per request, preserving <code>${VAR}</code> refs safely under concurrent gateway config mutations. (#11560) Thanks @akoscz.</li>
<li>Config: log overwrite audit entries (path, backup target, and hash transition) whenever an existing config file is replaced, improving traceability for unexpected config clobbers.</li>
<li>Config: keep legacy audio transcription migration strict by rejecting non-string/unsafe command tokens while still migrating valid custom script executables. (#5042) Thanks @shayan919293.</li>
<li>Config: accept <code>$schema</code> key in config file so JSON Schema editor tooling works without validation errors. (#14998)</li>
<li>Gateway/Tools Invoke: sanitize <code>/tools/invoke</code> execution failures while preserving <code>400</code> for tool input errors and returning <code>500</code> for unexpected runtime failures, with regression coverage and docs updates. (#13185) Thanks @davidrudduck.</li>
<li>Gateway/Hooks: preserve <code>408</code> for hook request-body timeout responses while keeping bounded auth-failure cache eviction behavior, with timeout-status regression coverage. (#15848) Thanks @AI-Reviewer-QS.</li>
<li>Plugins/Hooks: fire <code>before_tool_call</code> hook exactly once per tool invocation in embedded runs by removing duplicate dispatch paths while preserving parameter mutation semantics. (#15635) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Agents/Transcript policy: sanitize OpenAI/Codex tool-call ids during transcript policy normalization to prevent invalid tool-call identifiers from propagating into session history. (#15279) Thanks @divisonofficer.</li>
<li>Agents/Image tool: cap image-analysis completion <code>maxTokens</code> by model capability (<code>min(4096, model.maxTokens)</code>) to avoid over-limit provider failures while still preventing truncation. (#11770) Thanks @detecti1.</li>
<li>Agents/Compaction: centralize exec default resolution in the shared tool factory so per-agent <code>tools.exec</code> overrides (host/security/ask/node and related defaults) persist across compaction retries. (#15833) Thanks @napetrov.</li>
<li>Gateway/Agents: stop injecting a phantom <code>main</code> agent into gateway agent listings when <code>agents.list</code> explicitly excludes it. (#11450) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Process/Exec: avoid shell execution for <code>.exe</code> commands on Windows so env overrides work reliably in <code>runCommandWithTimeout</code>. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Daemon/Windows: preserve literal backslashes in <code>gateway.cmd</code> command parsing so drive and UNC paths are not corrupted in runtime checks and doctor entrypoint comparisons. (#15642) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Sandbox: pass configured <code>sandbox.docker.env</code> variables to sandbox containers at <code>docker create</code> time. (#15138) Thanks @stevebot-alive.</li>
<li>Voice Call: route webhook runtime event handling through shared manager event logic so rejected inbound hangups are idempotent in production, with regression tests for duplicate reject events and provider-call-ID remapping parity. (#15892) Thanks @dcantu96.</li>
<li>Cron: add regression coverage for announce-mode isolated jobs so runs that already report <code>delivered: true</code> do not enqueue duplicate main-session relays, including delivery configs where <code>mode</code> is omitted and defaults to announce. (#15737) Thanks @brandonwise.</li>
<li>Cron: honor <code>deleteAfterRun</code> in isolated announce delivery by mapping it to subagent announce cleanup mode, so cron run sessions configured for deletion are removed after completion. (#15368) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Web tools/web_fetch: prefer <code>text/markdown</code> responses for Cloudflare Markdown for Agents, add <code>cf-markdown</code> extraction for markdown bodies, and redact fetched URLs in <code>x-markdown-tokens</code> debug logs to avoid leaking raw paths/query params. (#15376) Thanks @Yaxuan42.</li>
<li>Clawdock: avoid Zsh readonly variable collisions in helper scripts. (#15501) Thanks @nkelner.</li>
<li>Memory: switch default local embedding model to the QAT <code>embeddinggemma-300m-qat-Q8_0</code> variant for better quality at the same footprint. (#15429) Thanks @azade-c.</li>
<li>Docs/Mermaid: remove hardcoded Mermaid init theme blocks from four docs diagrams so dark mode inherits readable theme defaults. (#15157) Thanks @heytulsiprasad.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.13/OpenClaw-2026.2.13.zip" length="22902077" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="RpkwlPtB2yN7UOYZWfthV5grhDUcbhcHMeicdRA864Vo/P0Hnq5aHKmSvcbWkjHut96TC57bX+AeUrL7txpLCg=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.12</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:17:54 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9500</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.12</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.12</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>CLI: add <code>openclaw logs --local-time</code> to display log timestamps in local timezone. (#13818) Thanks @xialonglee.</li>
<li>Telegram: render blockquotes as native <code><blockquote></code> tags instead of stripping them. (#14608)</li>
<li>Config: avoid redacting <code>maxTokens</code>-like fields during config snapshot redaction, preventing round-trip validation failures in <code>/config</code>. (#14006) Thanks @constansino.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Breaking</h3>
<ul>
<li>Hooks: <code>POST /hooks/agent</code> now rejects payload <code>sessionKey</code> overrides by default. To keep fixed hook context, set <code>hooks.defaultSessionKey</code> (recommended with <code>hooks.allowedSessionKeyPrefixes: ["hook:"]</code>). If you need legacy behavior, explicitly set <code>hooks.allowRequestSessionKey: true</code>. Thanks @alpernae for reporting.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Gateway/OpenResponses: harden URL-based <code>input_file</code>/<code>input_image</code> handling with explicit SSRF deny policy, hostname allowlists (<code>files.urlAllowlist</code> / <code>images.urlAllowlist</code>), per-request URL input caps (<code>maxUrlParts</code>), blocked-fetch audit logging, and regression coverage/docs updates.</li>
<li>Security: fix unauthenticated Nostr profile API remote config tampering. (#13719) Thanks @coygeek.</li>
<li>Security: remove bundled soul-evil hook. (#14757) Thanks @Imccccc.</li>
<li>Security/Audit: add hook session-routing hardening checks (<code>hooks.defaultSessionKey</code>, <code>hooks.allowRequestSessionKey</code>, and prefix allowlists), and warn when HTTP API endpoints allow explicit session-key routing.</li>
<li>Security/Sandbox: confine mirrored skill sync destinations to the sandbox <code>skills/</code> root and stop using frontmatter-controlled skill names as filesystem destination paths. Thanks @1seal.</li>
<li>Security/Web tools: treat browser/web content as untrusted by default (wrapped outputs for browser snapshot/tabs/console and structured external-content metadata for web tools), and strip <code>toolResult.details</code> from model-facing transcript/compaction inputs to reduce prompt-injection replay risk.</li>
<li>Security/Hooks: harden webhook and device token verification with shared constant-time secret comparison, and add per-client auth-failure throttling for hook endpoints (<code>429</code> + <code>Retry-After</code>). Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Security/Browser: require auth for loopback browser control HTTP routes, auto-generate <code>gateway.auth.token</code> when browser control starts without auth, and add a security-audit check for unauthenticated browser control. Thanks @tcusolle.</li>
<li>Sessions/Gateway: harden transcript path resolution and reject unsafe session IDs/file paths so session operations stay within agent sessions directories. Thanks @akhmittra.</li>
<li>Gateway: raise WS payload/buffer limits so 5,000,000-byte image attachments work reliably. (#14486) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Logging/CLI: use local timezone timestamps for console prefixing, and include <code>±HH:MM</code> offsets when using <code>openclaw logs --local-time</code> to avoid ambiguity. (#14771) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Gateway: drain active turns before restart to prevent message loss. (#13931) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Gateway: auto-generate auth token during install to prevent launchd restart loops. (#13813) Thanks @cathrynlavery.</li>
<li>Gateway: prevent <code>undefined</code>/missing token in auth config. (#13809) Thanks @asklee-klawd.</li>
<li>Gateway: handle async <code>EPIPE</code> on stdout/stderr during shutdown. (#13414) Thanks @keshav55.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI: resolve missing dashboard assets when <code>openclaw</code> is installed globally via symlink-based Node managers (nvm/fnm/n/Homebrew). (#14919) Thanks @aynorica.</li>
<li>Cron: use requested <code>agentId</code> for isolated job auth resolution. (#13983) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent cron jobs from skipping execution when <code>nextRunAtMs</code> advances. (#14068) Thanks @WalterSumbon.</li>
<li>Cron: pass <code>agentId</code> to <code>runHeartbeatOnce</code> for main-session jobs. (#14140) Thanks @ishikawa-pro.</li>
<li>Cron: re-arm timers when <code>onTimer</code> fires while a job is still executing. (#14233) Thanks @tomron87.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent duplicate fires when multiple jobs trigger simultaneously. (#14256) Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Cron: isolate scheduler errors so one bad job does not break all jobs. (#14385) Thanks @MarvinDontPanic.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent one-shot <code>at</code> jobs from re-firing on restart after skipped/errored runs. (#13878) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: prevent scheduler stalls on unexpected run errors and avoid immediate rerun loops after <code>requests-in-flight</code> skips. (#14901) Thanks @joeykrug.</li>
<li>Cron: honor stored session model overrides for isolated-agent runs while preserving <code>hooks.gmail.model</code> precedence for Gmail hook sessions. (#14983) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Logging/Browser: fall back to <code>os.tmpdir()/openclaw</code> for default log, browser trace, and browser download temp paths when <code>/tmp/openclaw</code> is unavailable.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: convert Markdown bold/strikethrough to WhatsApp formatting. (#14285) Thanks @Raikan10.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: allow media-only sends and normalize leading blank payloads. (#14408) Thanks @karimnaguib.</li>
<li>WhatsApp: default MIME type for voice messages when Baileys omits it. (#14444) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Telegram: handle no-text message in model picker editMessageText. (#14397) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Telegram: surface REACTION_INVALID as non-fatal warning. (#14340) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>BlueBubbles: fix webhook auth bypass via loopback proxy trust. (#13787) Thanks @coygeek.</li>
<li>Slack: change default replyToMode from "off" to "all". (#14364) Thanks @nm-de.</li>
<li>Slack: detect control commands when channel messages start with bot mention prefixes (for example, <code>@Bot /new</code>). (#14142) Thanks @beefiker.</li>
<li>Signal: enforce E.164 validation for the Signal bot account prompt so mistyped numbers are caught early. (#15063) Thanks @Duartemartins.</li>
<li>Discord: process DM reactions instead of silently dropping them. (#10418) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Discord: respect replyToMode in threads. (#11062) Thanks @cordx56.</li>
<li>Heartbeat: filter noise-only system events so scheduled reminder notifications do not fire when cron runs carry only heartbeat markers. (#13317) Thanks @pvtclawn.</li>
<li>Signal: render mention placeholders as <code>@uuid</code>/<code>@phone</code> so mention gating and Clawdbot targeting work. (#2013) Thanks @alexgleason.</li>
<li>Discord: omit empty content fields for media-only messages while preserving caption whitespace. (#9507) Thanks @leszekszpunar.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: add Z.AI endpoint-specific auth choices (<code>zai-coding-global</code>, <code>zai-coding-cn</code>, <code>zai-global</code>, <code>zai-cn</code>) and expand default Z.AI model wiring. (#13456) Thanks @tomsun28.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Providers: update MiniMax API default/recommended models from M2.1 to M2.5, add M2.5/M2.5-Lightning model entries, and include <code>minimax-m2.5</code> in modern model filtering. (#14865) Thanks @adao-max.</li>
<li>Ollama: use configured <code>models.providers.ollama.baseUrl</code> for model discovery and normalize <code>/v1</code> endpoints to the native Ollama API root. (#14131) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Voice Call: pass Twilio stream auth token via <code><Parameter></code> instead of query string. (#14029) Thanks @mcwigglesmcgee.</li>
<li>Feishu: pass <code>Buffer</code> directly to the Feishu SDK upload APIs instead of <code>Readable.from(...)</code> to avoid form-data upload failures. (#10345) Thanks @youngerstyle.</li>
<li>Feishu: trigger mention-gated group handling only when the bot itself is mentioned (not just any mention). (#11088) Thanks @openperf.</li>
<li>Feishu: probe status uses the resolved account context for multi-account credential checks. (#11233) Thanks @onevcat.</li>
<li>Feishu DocX: preserve top-level converted block order using <code>firstLevelBlockIds</code> when writing/appending documents. (#13994) Thanks @Cynosure159.</li>
<li>Feishu plugin packaging: remove <code>workspace:*</code> <code>openclaw</code> dependency from <code>extensions/feishu</code> and sync lockfile for install compatibility. (#14423) Thanks @jackcooper2015.</li>
<li>CLI/Wizard: exit with code 1 when <code>configure</code>, <code>agents add</code>, or interactive <code>onboard</code> wizards are canceled, so <code>set -e</code> automation stops correctly. (#14156) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Media: strip <code>MEDIA:</code> lines with local paths instead of leaking as visible text. (#14399) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Config/Cron: exclude <code>maxTokens</code> from config redaction and honor <code>deleteAfterRun</code> on skipped cron jobs. (#13342) Thanks @niceysam.</li>
<li>Config: ignore <code>meta</code> field changes in config file watcher. (#13460) Thanks @brandonwise.</li>
<li>Cron: use requested <code>agentId</code> for isolated job auth resolution. (#13983) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Cron: pass <code>agentId</code> to <code>runHeartbeatOnce</code> for main-session jobs. (#14140) Thanks @ishikawa-pro.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent cron jobs from skipping execution when <code>nextRunAtMs</code> advances. (#14068) Thanks @WalterSumbon.</li>
<li>Cron: re-arm timers when <code>onTimer</code> fires while a job is still executing. (#14233) Thanks @tomron87.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent duplicate fires when multiple jobs trigger simultaneously. (#14256) Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Cron: isolate scheduler errors so one bad job does not break all jobs. (#14385) Thanks @MarvinDontPanic.</li>
<li>Cron: prevent one-shot <code>at</code> jobs from re-firing on restart after skipped/errored runs. (#13878) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Daemon: suppress <code>EPIPE</code> error when restarting LaunchAgent. (#14343) Thanks @0xRaini.</li>
<li>Antigravity: add opus 4.6 forward-compat model and bypass thinking signature sanitization. (#14218) Thanks @jg-noncelogic.</li>
<li>Agents: prevent file descriptor leaks in child process cleanup. (#13565) Thanks @KyleChen26.</li>
<li>Agents: prevent double compaction caused by cache TTL bypassing guard. (#13514) Thanks @taw0002.</li>
<li>Agents: use last API call's cache tokens for context display instead of accumulated sum. (#13805) Thanks @akari-musubi.</li>
<li>Agents: keep followup-runner session <code>totalTokens</code> aligned with post-compaction context by using last-call usage and shared token-accounting logic. (#14979) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Hooks/Plugins: wire 9 previously unwired plugin lifecycle hooks into core runtime paths (session, compaction, gateway, and outbound message hooks). (#14882) Thanks @shtse8.</li>
<li>Hooks/Tools: dispatch <code>before_tool_call</code> and <code>after_tool_call</code> hooks from both tool execution paths with rebased conflict fixes. (#15012) Thanks @Patrick-Barletta, @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Discord: allow channel-edit to archive/lock threads and set auto-archive duration. (#5542) Thanks @stumct.</li>
<li>Discord tests: use a partial @buape/carbon mock in slash command coverage. (#13262) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Tests: update thread ID handling in Slack message collection tests. (#14108) Thanks @swizzmagik.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.12/OpenClaw-2026.2.12.zip" length="22877692" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="TGylTM4/7Lab+qp1nuPeOAmEVV1WkafXUPub8ws0z/0mYfbVygRuiev+u3zdPjQWhLnGYTgRgKVyW+kB2+Q2BQ=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.9</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:23:25 -0600</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>9194</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.9</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.9</h2>
<h3>Added</h3>
<ul>
<li>iOS: alpha node app + setup-code onboarding. (#11756) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Channels: comprehensive BlueBubbles and channel cleanup. (#11093) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Plugins: device pairing + phone control plugins (Telegram <code>/pair</code>, iOS/Android node controls). (#11755) Thanks @mbelinky.</li>
<li>Tools: add Grok (xAI) as a <code>web_search</code> provider. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Gateway: add agent management RPC methods for the web UI (<code>agents.create</code>, <code>agents.update</code>, <code>agents.delete</code>). (#11045) Thanks @advaitpaliwal.</li>
<li>Web UI: show a Compaction divider in chat history. (#11341) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: include runtime shell in agent envelopes. (#1835) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Paths: add <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code> for overriding the home directory used by internal path resolution. (#12091) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram: harden quote parsing; preserve quote context; avoid QUOTE_TEXT_INVALID; avoid nested reply quote misclassification. (#12156) Thanks @rybnikov.</li>
<li>Telegram: recover proactive sends when stale topic thread IDs are used by retrying without <code>message_thread_id</code>. (#11620)</li>
<li>Telegram: render markdown spoilers with <code><tg-spoiler></code> HTML tags. (#11543) Thanks @ezhikkk.</li>
<li>Telegram: truncate command registration to 100 entries to avoid <code>BOT_COMMANDS_TOO_MUCH</code> failures on startup. (#12356) Thanks @arosstale.</li>
<li>Telegram: match DM <code>allowFrom</code> against sender user id (fallback to chat id) and clarify pairing logs. (#12779) Thanks @liuxiaopai-ai.</li>
<li>Onboarding: QuickStart now auto-installs shell completion (prompt only in Manual).</li>
<li>Auth: strip embedded line breaks from pasted API keys and tokens before storing/resolving credentials.</li>
<li>Web UI: make chat refresh smoothly scroll to the latest messages and suppress new-messages badge flash during manual refresh.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: include provider-specific settings in the web search cache key, and pass <code>inlineCitations</code> for Grok. (#12419) Thanks @tmchow.</li>
<li>Tools/web_search: normalize direct Perplexity model IDs while keeping OpenRouter model IDs unchanged. (#12795) Thanks @cdorsey.</li>
<li>Model failover: treat HTTP 400 errors as failover-eligible, enabling automatic model fallback. (#1879) Thanks @orenyomtov.</li>
<li>Errors: prevent false positive context overflow detection when conversation mentions "context overflow" topic. (#2078) Thanks @sbking.</li>
<li>Gateway: no more post-compaction amnesia; injected transcript writes now preserve Pi session <code>parentId</code> chain so agents can remember again. (#12283) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Gateway: fix multi-agent sessions.usage discovery. (#11523) Thanks @Takhoffman.</li>
<li>Agents: recover from context overflow caused by oversized tool results (pre-emptive capping + fallback truncation). (#11579) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Subagents/compaction: stabilize announce timing and preserve compaction metrics across retries. (#11664) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron: share isolated announce flow and harden scheduling/delivery reliability. (#11641) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Cron tool: recover flat params when LLM omits the <code>job</code> wrapper for add requests. (#12124) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Gateway/CLI: when <code>gateway.bind=lan</code>, use a LAN IP for probe URLs and Control UI links. (#11448) Thanks @AnonO6.</li>
<li>Hooks: fix bundled hooks broken since 2026.2.2 (tsdown migration). (#9295) Thanks @patrickshao.</li>
<li>Routing: refresh bindings per message by loading config at route resolution so binding changes apply without restart. (#11372) Thanks @juanpablodlc.</li>
<li>Exec approvals: render forwarded commands in monospace for safer approval scanning. (#11937) Thanks @sebslight.</li>
<li>Config: clamp <code>maxTokens</code> to <code>contextWindow</code> to prevent invalid model configs. (#5516) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Thinking: allow xhigh for <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2-codex</code> and <code>github-copilot/gpt-5.2</code>. (#11646) Thanks @LatencyTDH.</li>
<li>Discord: support forum/media thread-create starter messages, wire <code>message thread create --message</code>, and harden routing. (#10062) Thanks @jarvis89757.</li>
<li>Paths: structurally resolve <code>OPENCLAW_HOME</code>-derived home paths and fix Windows drive-letter handling in tool meta shortening. (#12125) Thanks @mcaxtr.</li>
<li>Memory: set Voyage embeddings <code>input_type</code> for improved retrieval. (#10818) Thanks @mcinteerj.</li>
<li>Memory/QMD: reuse default model cache across agents instead of re-downloading per agent. (#12114) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Media understanding: recognize <code>.caf</code> audio attachments for transcription. (#10982) Thanks @succ985.</li>
<li>State dir: honor <code>OPENCLAW_STATE_DIR</code> for default device identity and canvas storage paths. (#4824) Thanks @kossoy.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.9/OpenClaw-2026.2.9.zip" length="22872529" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="zvgwqlgqI7J5Gsi9VSULIQTMKqLiGE5ulC6NnRLKtOPphQsHZVdYSWm0E90+Yq8mG4lpsvbxQOSSPxpl43QTAw=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>